const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of a life-threatening condition in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory rate > 25/min","bool":true},{"option":"Silent chest","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following features, according to Light's criteria, is suggestive of exudative effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural fluid protein : serum protein ratio < 0.5","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH < 2/3 of upper limit of normal serum LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid glucose is higher than serum glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH : serum LDH ratio > 0.6","bool":true},{"option":"Protein content of fluid < 30 g/L","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Administration of which of the following vitamins is important for measles infection?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B9","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B1","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What type of emphysema is caused by smoking?","answers":[{"option":"Irregular","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Centriacinar","bool":true},{"option":"Distal acinar","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following drugs is a 5-lipoxygenase pathway inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Monteluklast","bool":false},{"option":"Omalizumab","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Cromolyn","bool":false},{"option":"Theophylline","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Wegener's granulomatosis affects what organ systems?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory and reproductive","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory and renal","bool":true},{"option":"Musculoskeletal and gastrointestinal","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal and reproductive","bool":false},{"option":"Nervous and renal","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the appearance of squamous cells?","answers":[{"option":"Star-shaped cells","bool":false},{"option":"Small Y-shaped cells","bool":false},{"option":"Longitudinally stretched cells","bool":false},{"option":"Small round cells","bool":true},{"option":"Barrel-shaped cells","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a centrally acting antitussive?","answers":[{"option":"Opioids","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled steam","bool":true},{"option":"Codeine","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocodone","bool":false},{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the causative agent of air-conditioning-associated pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the most common cause of ventilator-associated pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Kleibsella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms is most likely to cause pneumonia associated with a lung abscess?","answers":[{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is true about adipocere?","answers":[{"option":"Highly acidic soil prevents adipocere formation","bool":false},{"option":"Adipoceres always have a hard and cracked appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Cold temperature favors adipocere formation","bool":false},{"option":"Caused by hydrolysis and hydrogenation","bool":true},{"option":"Anaerobic conditions inhibit adipocere","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of these is not a feature seen in the eyes after death?","answers":[{"option":"Cattle trucking of retinal vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Opacity of the cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Flaccidity of the eyeball","bool":false},{"option":"Gradual decline in vitreal potassium levels","bool":true},{"option":"Taches noires on the sclera","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a second-line tuberculosis drug?","answers":[{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"If a person stands behind a thin cotton curtain, which radiation will he be protected from?","answers":[{"option":"X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Neutron","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha","bool":true},{"option":"Beta","bool":false},{"option":"Gamma","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the optimum temperature range for putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"80 °F and 90 °F","bool":false},{"option":"70 °F and 100 °F","bool":true},{"option":"60 °F and 100 °F","bool":false},{"option":"70 °F and 110 °F","bool":false},{"option":"50 °F and 100 °F","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is nosocomial pneumonia also known as?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Hospital acquired pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the most common cause of community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Legionella pneumophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the first to undergo putrefaction after death?","answers":[{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"In which of the following diseases does the total lung capacity decrease?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What does Casper's dictum mean?","answers":[{"option":"Cause of putrefaction","bool":false},{"option":"Rate of putrefaction","bool":true},{"option":"Cause of death","bool":false},{"option":"Time of death","bool":false},{"option":"Degree of mutilation","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A 30-year-old female receiving anti-tuberculosis drugs complains of disturbance in vision and loss of visual acuity. Which of the following drugs would have caused this?","answers":[{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A dead body is discovered lying hidden amongst bushes in a supine position, with postmortem lividity fully established, and black in color. In the given scenario, which area of the body will not demonstrate the postmortem lividity?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital scalp","bool":true},{"option":"Sacral region","bool":false},{"option":"Hands","bool":false},{"option":"Neck","bool":false},{"option":"Back of ears","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of action of methylxanthines?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of phosphodiesterase","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":true},{"option":"Activation of adenosine receptors","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is acid rain caused by?","answers":[{"option":"Cow dung","bool":false},{"option":"Global warming","bool":false},{"option":"Increased sulfur dioxide","bool":true},{"option":"Increased carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Coal","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A false negative purified protein derivative (PPD) test is NOT found in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Prior Bacille Calmette-Guérin (BCG) vaccination","bool":true},{"option":"In malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"In newborns","bool":false},{"option":"In malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"In Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) positive tests","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about smokers' macrophages?","answers":[{"option":"Dusty brown pigment in macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Finely granular iron may be seen in cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Presenting symptom is dyspnea and productive cough","bool":true},{"option":"Surfactant found in phagocytic vacuoles","bool":false},{"option":"Feature of desquamative interstitial pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Exposure to asbestos will not lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchogenic cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the narrowest part of the pediatric airway?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Subglottic area","bool":false},{"option":"Cricoid ring","bool":true},{"option":"Glottis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common occupational lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Asymptomatic anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive massive fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which type of hypersensitivity is being displayed in a positive Mantoux test?","answers":[{"option":"Type II","bool":false},{"option":"Type VI","bool":false},{"option":"Type IV","bool":true},{"option":"Type I","bool":false},{"option":"Type III","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following anti-tuberculosis drugs causes ototoxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following are avoided during chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Long-acting beta-agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Short-acting beta-agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Anticholinergics","bool":false},{"option":"Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following gases is not released during putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Methane","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen sulfide","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the optimum temperature range for putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"21-38°C","bool":true},{"option":"10-38°C","bool":false},{"option":"27-33°C","bool":false},{"option":"21-44°C","bool":false},{"option":"16-38°C","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the first sign of putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Greenish discoloration of the skin","bool":true},{"option":"Extrusion of hair and nails","bool":false},{"option":"Slippage of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of blisters","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the cause of panacinar emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Exposure to air pollutants","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Past severe infection","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive smoking","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is postmortem lividity?","answers":[{"option":"Pooling of blood in dependent parts of the body after death","bool":true},{"option":"Decomposition of body tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Stiffening of body muscles","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Gradual cooling of the body after death","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Stiffening of body muscles","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pooling of blood in dependent parts of the body after death","bool":false},{"option":"Decomposition of body tissues","bool":true},{"option":"Gradual cooling of the body after death","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following anti-tuberculous drugs is bactericidal?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Para amino salicylic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What disease is characterized by Charcot Leyden crystals and Curschmann's spirals found in sputum?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following antituberculous drug causes joint pain?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifabutin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following types of cancer is likely to develop from asbestosis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural solitary fibrous tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant mesothelioma","bool":true},{"option":"Oropharyngeal carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Vestibular toxicity is associated with which of the following drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Rifabutin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A 35-year-old female brings her pleural fluid analysis report, which shows the exudative nature of pleural fluid with a high amylase level. She gives a history of upper abdominal pain and vomiting in the recent past. She also had pulmonary tuberculosis 10 years ago. She has now developed pleural effusion. What is the most likely cause of her current condition?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute cholecystitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Caplan syndrome is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false},{"option":"Barium sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":true},{"option":"Bagasse","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"An adult woman presented to an ophthalmologist with decreased visual acuity and color blindness for green. She has been on anti-tuberculous therapy (ATT) for 1 month. Her fundoscopy was normal. The ophthalmologist asked her to stop which of the following drugs considering the cause of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Radiation hazard most commonly leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Shortening of life always","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia only","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic changes and malformations","bool":true},{"option":"Death due to chronic liver failure","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which condition is associated with Pneumocystis pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Alcoholism","bool":false},{"option":"AIDS","bool":true},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragmatic hernia","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Bronchiectasis is associated with which of the following syndromes?","answers":[{"option":"Reye's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Broken heart syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Kartagener's syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A 26-year-old housewife develops a high-grade fever, cough with purulent sputum, and pleuritic type of chest pain. The lady was previously in a good state of health. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Acute exacerbation of chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Syndrome of inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion (SIADH) and ectopic adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) secretion are paraneoplastic syndromes. These are associated with which type of bronchogenic carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following subtype of lung cancer is most commonly found in females?","answers":[{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoids","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What condition is associated with situs inversus?","answers":[{"option":"Dextrocardia","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder exstrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Right-sided liver","bool":false},{"option":"Dandy-Walker syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Biliary atresia","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with a lowered diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO)?","answers":[{"option":"Polio","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung diseases","bool":true},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Asthma is associated with what type of infiltrate?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophilic","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilic","bool":true},{"option":"Basophilic","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytic","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What interleukin causes eosinophilia?","answers":[{"option":"IL-8","bool":false},{"option":"IL-23","bool":false},{"option":"IL-10","bool":false},{"option":"IL-5","bool":true},{"option":"IL-12","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of corticosteroid therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease cAMP hydrolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Prevent mast cell degranulation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit PDE-5 synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of NF-κβ","bool":true},{"option":"Bind serum IgE","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Malignant mesothelioma is associated with exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Copper dust","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true},{"option":"Lead","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Pneumoconiosis are often which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hereditary","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversible","bool":true},{"option":"Multi-system","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Reversible","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What pathology increases susceptibility to tuberculosis (TB)?","answers":[{"option":"Beryllosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hemochromatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Black lung disease","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Bilateral hilar lymphadenopathy is seen in which of the following pathologies?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes virus","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the key histological finding in sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Caseating granulomas","bool":false},{"option":"Dumbbell shaped cytoplasmic inclusions","bool":false},{"option":"Signet ring shaped cells","bool":false},{"option":"Non-caseating granulomas","bool":true},{"option":"Teardrop shaped cells","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of bacterial resistance to rifampin?","answers":[{"option":"Alteration in cell wall synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Efflux of drug","bool":false},{"option":"Alteration in DNA synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Alteration in DNA dependent RNA polymerase gene","bool":true},{"option":"Alteration mutation of Kat G","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the adverse effect most commonly associated with ethambutol?","answers":[{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Parkinsonism","bool":false},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Arthalgia","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"An individual comes in with sudden onset high fever and cough with sputum, what is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella infection","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arhtritis","bool":false},{"option":"Community acquired pneumonia","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the major source of farmer's lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Moldy cheese","bool":false},{"option":"Hemp","bool":false},{"option":"Moldy hay","bool":true},{"option":"Ecstacy","bool":false},{"option":"Avian excreta","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"The type of asphyxia that is associated with anesthesia and surgical maneuvers is termed as:","answers":[{"option":"Toxic asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Pathological asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Iatrogenic asphyxia","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What does the common radiological finding in the case of epiglottitis show?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"steeple sign\"","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral nonhomogeneous infiltrations in both lungs with shifting of trachea on right side","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"thumb printing sign\"","bool":true},{"option":"X-ray neck AP-view reveals \" steeple sign\"","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray chest shows bilateral hilar infiltration with shifting of trachea toward left side","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which statement is incorrect about olfactory cells?","answers":[{"option":"Have Bowman's glands secreting mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Mucosal ends have cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Are stimulated by mechanical stimulus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Are bipolar neurons","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Where is the first sign of internal putrefaction seen?","answers":[{"option":"Under surface of the liver","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"In which of the following disease, FEV1/FVC below 0.7 with an increased total lung capacity, is seen?","answers":[{"option":"Obstructive lung disease","bool":true},{"option":"Restrictive lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonitis","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the method of action of montelukast?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibits the cysteinyl leukotriene CysLT1 receptor","bool":true},{"option":"Cytokine receptor anatognist","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene receptor agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents the release of granules from mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cytokine receptor agonist","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Pneumothorax is most commonly associated with:","answers":[{"option":"Underlying malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema, asthma and tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos exposure","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the maximum volume of air that can be expelled after normal expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":true},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a criterion for clinical diagnosis of death?","answers":[{"option":"Absence of pulse","bool":false},{"option":"Fixed dilated pupils","bool":false},{"option":"A loss of brainstem reflexes","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of breathing","bool":false},{"option":"A flat electroencephalogram (EEG)","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What stain is used for Mycobacterium tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ziehl–Neelsen stain","bool":true},{"option":"Congo red capsule stain","bool":false},{"option":"Endospore stain","bool":false},{"option":"Hematoxylin and eosin stain","bool":false},{"option":"Gram-negative stain","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is an interferon-gamma release assay used to diagnose?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Latent tuberculosis infection","bool":true},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the drug of choice for the treatment of bacterial pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Penicillins","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporins","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoroquinolones","bool":false},{"option":"Macrolides","bool":true},{"option":"Aminoglycosides","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Highest p53 mutations are found in which type of lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoma in situ","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What causes epithelial damage in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Eotaxin","bool":false},{"option":"Chemokines","bool":false},{"option":"Increased mucus","bool":false},{"option":"Major basic protein","bool":true},{"option":"Bradykinin","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What are the acute effects of poor illumination/lighting?","answers":[{"option":"Blurred vision","bool":false},{"option":"Discomfort","bool":false},{"option":"Fatigue","bool":false},{"option":"Minor nystagmus","bool":false},{"option":"Headache and eye pain","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"How is an epiglottis infection treated?","answers":[{"option":"Racemic epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Mist therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Antiviral medications","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is true about transudative effusion?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gravity of fluid is more than 1.102","bool":false},{"option":"Serum LDH ratio is >0.6","bool":false},{"option":"Protein content is <2.5 g/dL","bool":true},{"option":"Protein content is >2.5 g/dL","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following will not be effective in the management of an acute asthma attack?","answers":[{"option":"Oral corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"LABA","bool":false},{"option":"IV corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Oral leukotriene receptor antagonist","bool":true},{"option":"SABA","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which type of cancer gives the best response to chemotherapy?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell lung carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Non-carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not seen in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Nocturnal cough","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic dyspnea","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial breathing","bool":true},{"option":"Wheezing","bool":false},{"option":"Tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is true about rigor mortis?","answers":[{"option":"It is also called instantaneous rigor","bool":false},{"option":"It is the stiffening of body muscles after death","bool":true},{"option":"It is called false mortis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It occurs 48 hours after death","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following drugs result in color blindness?","answers":[{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of lung tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Non-small cell lung carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Small cell lung carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Solitary fibrous tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic of small cell carcinoma of the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Keratin pearls and intercellular bridges","bool":false},{"option":"Lepidic growth pattern of tall columnar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Undifferentiated malignant epithelial tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Round or oval cells with scant cytoplasm and nuclear molding (salt and pepper appearance)","bool":true},{"option":"Lepidic growth pattern of cuboidal cells","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not an example of a paraneoplastic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Clubbing","bool":false},{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombophlebitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not associated with diffuse parenchymal lung diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Shortness of breath","bool":false},{"option":"Joint pain","bool":false},{"option":"Clubbing","bool":false},{"option":"Productive cough","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is used to determine ventilation abnormalities?","answers":[{"option":"Forced expiratory volume","bool":true},{"option":"Total lung capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following radiological findings is characteristic of tracheolaryngobronchitis?","answers":[{"option":"Thumb printing sign","bool":false},{"option":"Steeple sign","bool":true},{"option":"Consolidation","bool":false},{"option":"Bird beak sign","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperinflation of lungs","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Asbestosis is not associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural plaques","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A coal mine worker develops chest pain which decreases their ability to work. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Coal workers' pneumoconiosis","bool":true}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the best indicator of air pollution?","answers":[{"option":"Sulphur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Methane","bool":false},{"option":"Particulate matter","bool":true},{"option":"Smoke, suspended particles and sulfur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a complication of pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchogenic carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Empyema","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following statements is true?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumothorax refers to accumulation of air within the pleural cavity","bool":true},{"option":"Chylothorax refers to accumulation of pus within the pleural cavity","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrothorax refers to accumulation of lymphatic fluid within the pleural cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Hemothorax refers to accumulation of fluid within the pleural cavity","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is meant by ergonomics?","answers":[{"option":"Fitting worker to the surroundings","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the surroundings to the worker","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the job to the worker","bool":true},{"option":"Fitting the job to the surroundings","bool":false},{"option":"Fitting the worker to the job","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the below enlisted is the most significant occupational hazard from long-term ionizing radiation exposure?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased libido","bool":false},{"option":"Flushed skin","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic changes","bool":true},{"option":"Hair loss","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased sperm","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What occupational hazard is associated with welding?","answers":[{"option":"Carditis","bool":false},{"option":"Conjuctivitis","bool":true},{"option":"Gingivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Orchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleuritis","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the pathology of bronchiectasis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute necrotizing infections","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic pyogenic infections","bool":false},{"option":"Increased ciliary movement","bool":false},{"option":"Type I hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic necrotizing infections","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"When is a gastric lavage contraindicated?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin overdose","bool":false},{"option":"Carbolic acid poisioning","bool":false},{"option":"Corrosive poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Iron tablet overdose","bool":false},{"option":"Blood meal","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is Mikulicz syndrome characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the perineum","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the thorax","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the limbs","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal enlargement of glands in the head and neck","bool":true}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"ICU admission for a patient with pneumonia is indicated with which CURB-65 score?","answers":[{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4 or more","bool":false},{"option":"3 or more","bool":true},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What level of the respiratory tract is choking seen at?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Glottis","bool":true},{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nose and mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Main bronchus","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a cause of hypersensitivity pneumonitis?","answers":[{"option":"Viral infections","bool":false},{"option":"Inorganic dust","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled organic antigens","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following arteries is most commonly blocked in autopsy in case of coronary atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Circumflex artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true},{"option":"Right coronary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a cause of centriacinar emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Viral infections","bool":false},{"option":"Inorganic dust","bool":false},{"option":"Organic antigens","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1 anti-trypsin deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is not a systemic manifestation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic liver disease","bool":true},{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle wasting","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the most common site of the formation of noncaseating granuloma in sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Skin","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is caused by saddle embolus?","answers":[{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Chest pain","bool":false},{"option":"Sudden death","bool":true},{"option":"Nosebleed","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the most common causative organism of bacterial pneumonia in children?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A 50-year-old male works at a coal mine for the past 7 years. He is also a  smoker. He presents with complaints of progressive dyspnea and pulmonary hypertension. His biopsy shows extensive carbon-laden macrophages with extensive fibrosis. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Coal workers' pneumoconiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the correct interpretation of arterial blood gases when pH is 7.50, PCO2 is 16 mmHg and bicarbonate is 26 mmol?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A 2-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with a barking cough and hoarseness of voice. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute laryngotracheitis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pharyngitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute epiglottitis","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following are complications of asbestosis?","answers":[{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural and lung cancers","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac arrhythmias","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a complication of silicosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Coughing","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the major pathologic change of small airway disease?","answers":[{"option":"Airspace enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Airway dilation and scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory obliteration","bool":true},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous gland hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of these is not a risk factor for tuberculosis in children?","answers":[{"option":"Enclosed, poorly ventilated spaces","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac problems","bool":true},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Close contact with affected person","bool":false},{"option":"Positive skin test","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is true about terbutaline?","answers":[{"option":"It is a vasoconstrictor","bool":false},{"option":"It is a beta-2 antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is a bronchodilator","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following investigations are done to confirm tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Purified protein derivative skin test","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum staining","bool":false},{"option":"Lung biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"3 morning sputum samples taken for sputum culture","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a differentiating point between chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchodilator reversibility >15% in COPD","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma is a restrictive lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Diurnal variation is present in COPD","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilator reversibility >15% in asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Allergic rhinitis is a feature of asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the best first-line diagnostic test for pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"Electrocardiography","bool":false},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":false},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT) pulmonary angiography","bool":true},{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of methylxanthines?","answers":[{"option":"Activation of adenosine receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of phospholipase C","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of phosphodiesterase","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease in cAMP","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"A diver has a condition that arises from dissolved gases coming out of solution into bubbles upon depressurization of the body. What is this condition known as?","answers":[{"option":"Drowning","bool":false},{"option":"Caisson disease","bool":true},{"option":"Diving disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cow's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Carrion disease","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is an example of a negative autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Vascular rejection of cardiac allograft","bool":false},{"option":"Penetrating fragment injuries in explosion","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following organisms is responsible for putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Spirochaetes","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydiae","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium welchii","bool":true},{"option":"Listeria monocytogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following causes bronchiolitis?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory syncytial virus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Allergy","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the primary lesion in tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hilar lymphadenopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Apical patchy shadowing","bool":false},{"option":"Ghon complex","bool":true},{"option":"Small pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary mottling","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the mechanism of beta agonists?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilation","bool":true}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is cadaveric spasm?","answers":[{"option":"Cooling of dead body","bool":false},{"option":"Body pallor","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle stiffening at the time of death","bool":true},{"option":"Breakdown of body tissues","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"What is the first external sign of putrefaction?","answers":[{"option":"Postmortem luminescence","bool":false},{"option":"Greenish discoloration over the right iliac fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Distension","bool":false},{"option":"Marbling of skin","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a long-acting beta-agonist?","answers":[{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is a rare site of lung cancer metastasis?","answers":[{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal glands","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2018","question":"Which of the following is the best X-ray view for pneumothorax?","answers":[{"option":"Anteroposterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]}]
export default arr